

## GARRETT C. MILLAR

UX/HCI RESEARCHER

#### CONTACT



RALEIGH. NC



GCMILLAR.GITHUB.IO



GCMILLAR@NCSU.EDU



(336) 202-5732

#### SKILLS

UX RESEARCH & DESIGN

HCI RESEARCH METHODS

**JAVASCRIPT** 

**PYTHON** 

GIS

**STATISTICS** 

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

DATA VISUALIZATION

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE

#### COURSES

HUMAN FACTORS METHODS STATISTICS I, II, III

ERGONOMIC PERFORMANCE ASSESSMENT

COGNITIVE PROCESSES
PHYSIOLOGICAL PSYCHOLOGY
COGNITIVE SCIENCE

#### PROFILE



A collaborator and researcher with a passion for innovation across a wide variety of platforms. With an inquisitive and empathetic nature, and a background in psychology, computer science, and graphic design, I seek to understand and communicate the human needs, behaviors, motivations, and the physical and cognitive factors that impact the design and function of things. With 8 years in UX / HCI research and design, human computer interaction, computer science, and design strategy, I bring a strong strategic mindset that connects science and art with a core value of user-centered design.

#### EDUCATION



2018 — 2021 | DOCTORATE OF PHILOSOPHY a,\*

Geospatial Analytics

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

## 2016 — 2018 | DOCTORATE OF PHILOSOPHY b,\*

Psychology — Human Factors & Applied Cognition North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

#### 2012 — 2016 | BACHELOR OF ARTS

Psychology

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

### WORK EXPERIENCE



#### 2021 — PRESENT | USER EXPERIENCE RESEARCHER

LENOVO — MORRISVILLE, NORTH CAROLINA, UNITED STATES

- Lead and conduct UX research across a wide range of website UIs, customer types, and product information.
- Perform competitive analysis, benchmarking, contextual inquiry and other advanced types of usability tests.

# 2017 — PRESENT | GRADUATE RESEARCH & TEACHING ASSISTANT

CENTER FOR GEOSPATIAL ANALYTICS — NC STATE UNIVERSITY

- Develop, plan, and manage participatory workshops to understand and resolve user needs encountered during the use of web-mapping platforms.
- Design and develop visual tools and features for new GUI and startup-screen to enable intuitive software use for all user levels.

### 2016 — 2017 | GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

LABORATORY FOR THE STUDY OF METACOGNITION & ADVANCED LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES — NC STATE UNIVERSITY

 Designed, developed, and tested intelligent tutoring systems with virtual agents to promote college students' STEM learning.

## SELECTED PUBLICATIONS



Millar, G. C., Mitas, O., Boode, W., Hoeke, L., de Kruijf, J., Petrasova, A., & Mitasova, H. (2021). Space-time analytics of human physiology for urban planning. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 85, 101554.

Millar, G. C., Tabrizian P., Petrasova A., Petras V., Harmon B., Mitasova H., Meetenmeyer R. K. (2018). Tangible landscape: A hands-on method for teaching terrain analysis. In Proceedings of the 2018 chi conference on human factors in computing systems (pp. 380:1–380:12). New York, NY, USA: ACM. [Winner of the Honorable Mention for Best Paper Award].

Pryor, M., **Millar, G. C.,** McNamara, A., Kaufman, L., & McLaughlin, A. C. (2017, September). Creating content guidelines for consistent display of information on an ecommerce website. In Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting (Vol. 61, No. 1, pp. 1834-1838). Sage CA: Los Angeles, CA: SAGE Publications.

a,\*Expected defense Fall 2021.

b,\* Transferred from Human Factors and Applied Cognition to Geospatial Analytics in February 2018.